TÁR is a music, drama film directed by Todd Field.
As celebrated conductor Lydia Tár starts rehearsals for a career-defining symphony,
the consequences of her past choices begin to echo in the present.
Lydia Tár, played by Cate Blanchett.
Sharon Goodnow, played by Nina Hoss.
Francesca Lentini, played by Noémie Merlant.
Olga Metkina, played by Sophie Kauer.
Andris Davis, played by Julian Glover.
Eliot Kaplan, played by Mark Strong.
Tár is a 2022 psychological drama film written and directed by Todd Field.
Cate Blanchett stars as Lydia Tár, a world-renowned conductor, whose
life unravels after she is accused of misconduct.
The supporting cast includes Nina Hoss, Noémie Merlant, Sophie
Kauer, Julian Glover, Allan Corduner, and Mark Strong.
Tár premiered at the 79th Venice International Film Festival in September
2022, where Blanchett won the Volpi Cup for Best Actress.
Following a three-week limited theatrical release, it received a wide
release on October 28, 2022, through Focus Features.
Tár received critical acclaim, especially for Blanchett's
performance and Field's screenplay and direction.
At the 95th Academy Awards, Tár was nominated for
6 awards, including Best Picture.
Blanchett won the BAFTA, Golden Globe, and Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best Actress, and was
nominated for the Academy Award and Screen Actors Guild Award in the same category.
Since its release, it has been regarded as one of the
greatest films of the 2020s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of infidelity, new york city,
berlin, germany, composer, musician.
The tone is emotional and intense.